RENE ENRIQUE MEJIA DIGITAL MARKETING



https://insertmorecoffee.com/

Profile

Hi! I'm René Mejía, I have **8+ years of experience** in both **web development** and **digital marketing**. I have had the privilege of working with international teams, building my own team, dealing with clients, and presenting results to boards of directors.

Some of my digital marketing skills are: managing social media and programmatic campaigns, analyzing campaign results, pacing, and customer behavior, marketing automation, lead generation, On-page SEO strategies, email marketing and content marketing strategies using Inbound Marketing.

Work experience

10/2021 - PRESENT

Advertising Operations Specialist SRAX

Providing advertising solutions for publicly traded companies looking to attract investors and increase brand awareness.

- Developed and managed trafficking campaigns across multiple platforms.
- Monitored campaign performance and optimized accordingly.
- Coordinated with cross-functional teams to ensure campaign success.
- Ran daily, weekly and monthly ad operations reports for multiple clients.
- Monitored client spend and provided recommendations for optimization.
- Collaborated with internal teams to identify and resolve technical issues.
- QA'd ad units before launch and provided feedback to Ad Ops and Creative teams.
- Led training sessions for new hires on ad serving platforms

Work experience

12/2018 - 10/2021

Digital Marketing Strategist / Innovation & Development Manager Santinos Digital

Planning, guiding and executing multichannel digital marketing campaigns for the agency's premium clients

- Exploration of the business needs with the management team and the client's sales team.
- Design of the strategy hand in hand with the client's visionary team.
- Creation of the project, delivery dates and scope.
- Ran daily, weekly and monthly ad operations reports for multiple clients.
- Developed and executed marketing plans to increase brand awareness and drive sales.
- Planned and executed email marketing campaigns to generate leads and increase conversion rates.

Responsible for the agency's web products, marketing automation, lead generation and Inbound Marketing strategies.

- Web design team leader.
- Implementation of new tools and methodologies.
- Integration between the different advertising tools of the agency.
- Design of automated flows for inbound marketing strategies.
- Detailed campaign reports and marketing analytics.
- · Sales.

Education

08/2010 - 11/2014 MEXICALI, MEXICO

Bachelor of Computer Science Universidad Autónoma de Baja California